# Adam Jackrel

# Technology Educator / Creative Technologist

Phone: 845-797-1854 Email: ajackrel@gmail.com

Web Portfolio: http://www.adamjackrel.com

# About Me

Obsessed with technology and emerging trends in physical computing, digital spaces, and human interaction. Always have my hands in some new project. I love sharing my personal and artistic projects in the classroom; diving into the theory of how it all works, then letting students take the reins to make something themselves. The satisfaction I feel when I experience a student growing into their own is immense and I feel lucky to be apart of that student's journey.

# Work Experience

# Silicon Valley Design and Technology

Founder

January 2022 - Present

An after-school and mentorship program designed to help students pursue their own interests and passions in the Design and Technology world.

### Silicon Valley International School

Upper School Design Teacher August 2021 - August 2022

Taught 7 sections of Design and Design Technology in the MYP (6th-10th) and DP Programs (11th and 12th). Co-advisor of an 8th grade advisory. Designed, implemented, and maintained a Makerspace for grades 6-12.

# Friends Seminary

Upper School Technology Integrator and Computer Science Teacher August 2019 - June 2020 (ONE-YEAR APPOINTMENT)

Working with the Technology Team to define and develop the role of technology in the classroom. Evaluating hardware and software for students and faculty. Taught 3 classes: Intro to Programming sections and advanced classes in Game Design and iOS Programming.

# Creative Arts Program at Berkeley Carroll

Technology Teacher
June 2019 - August 2019

Summer teacher for students grade 3-9. Taught four classes: LEGO Robotics I and II, Fashion Wearables, and Meme Creator

#### Freelancer

Creative Technology and Software Development April 2015 - August 2019

Worked on a variety of projects for private, public, and commercial clients.

Some notable projects include LED suits for Taylor Swift's 1989 Tour and Burning Man 2015/16/17/18, a Video LED Cube for BangOn! Event Productions, an LED Visual EQ for VH1 cable station, and a touch-interactive map for the Lewis and Clark Historic Site in Great Falls. Missouri.

#### Avenues: The World School

iLab Technician (Makerspace Educator / Manager)

August 2016 - August 2018

Co-managed two makerspaces for Middle and Upper School students. Instructed students and faculty on the safe use of tools and equipment. Maintained a widevariety of tools, materials, and equipment. Designed, planned, and executed lesson plans for a variety of cross-disciplinary classes.

# Education

New York University New York, New York BA in Computer Science and Game Design August 2011 - May 2015

	Design Skills								
Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe InDesign Adobe Flash	•	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>	_	0 0 0	0 0 0
Coding Skills									
HTML5 & CSS3 Javascript/jQuery iOS/Swift Processing Java Bootstrap Express (MEAN) C/C++/C#	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>							00000000	0000000
Physi	cal C	om	ıρι	ıtir	ng S	Ski	ls		
Arduino Raspberry Pi Beaglebone Micro-Controllers Electronics Soldering	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>						
	Fabrication Skills								
3D Printing Laser Cutting /Rastering Rhino CAD Wood/Metal Fabrication	•	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>	<ul><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li><li>•</li></ul>						
Gr	ants	an	d <i>A</i>	\Wa	arc	ls	_		

# January 2014

Awarded the Tisch Graduate Student Organization Interdepartmental Grant to create a new, interactive performance piece.

#### October 2014

Awarded the NYU Prototype Fund grant for an energy sensing and automation platform.

#### November 2014

Awarded the Dean's Undergraduate Research Fund grant for an energy sensing and automation platform